<Document>
#Prometheus Protocol
For the uninformed, the [bold][color=darkred]Prometheus Protocol[/bold][/color] is a step-by-step procedure for a last-ditch effort against whatever threat has gotten severe enough to 
consider detonation of the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device.[/bold][/color] 

[bold][color=red]It is not to be taken lightly and must only be utilized if it is absolutely necessary.[/bold][/color]

- Certain [bold][color=violet]Concord Frontier Authority Quarantine Protocols[/bold][/color] demand the detonation of the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] to 
halt the spread of any biological life, disease or otherwise that is or could be considered sector-ending, 
or even civilization-ending, that the Station has failed to contain on their own.

##Step One -
[bold][color=#e6b363]The Captain[/bold][/color] & [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Head of Security[/bold][/color] must come to a collective agreement the situation is unsalvageable. 

Unsalvageable is defined as;
- Stationside [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] being entirely unable to handle the threat, or already mostly if not entirely eliminated by the threat.
- Most of the Station deceased or under hostile influence.
- Emergency Response Teams being ineffective for the situation.
- Or [bold][color=violet]CFA Quarantine Protocol[/bold][/color].

##Step Two -
Once the agreement is made, whatever remains of [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color] must be called to bridge for a 
meeting about the impending situation. [bold][color=red]Operate under the assumption Communications have been 
compromised[/bold][/color] and do not reveal the true nature of the meeting over the Radio.

Once the situation has been explained, the decision to detonate the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] must be put to a vote within [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color]. 
- If the [bold][color=darkred]Prometheus Protocol[/bold][/color] was forced by a [bold][color=violet]CFA Quarantine Protocol[/bold][/color], 
the Protocol must be continued regardless unless the [bold][color=#e6b363]Magistrate[/bold][/color] objects.

- [bold][color=green]Majority Agreement[/bold][/color] - The [bold][color=darkred]Prometheus Protocol[/bold][/color] can be continued.
- [bold][color=red]Majority Disagreement[/bold][/color] - The [bold][color=darkred]Prometheus Protocol[/bold][/color] cannot be continued. However, it can still be overruled by the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]NanoTransen Representative[/bold][/color] if they agree with the [bold][color=#e6b363]Captain[/bold][/color] & [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Head of Security[/bold][/color]’s argument. 
- [color=yellow]Minority/Tie[/color] - The vote of the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]NanoTransen Representative[/bold][/color] will act as a tiebreaker.

##Step Three -
You must then send a fax to [bold][color=#1E4F19]Central Command[/bold][/color] with the results of the vote, or if it was a forced procedure, 
that you are following [bold][color=violet]CFA Quarantine Protocols[/bold][/color]. Give a detailed explanation as to why the situation onboard the 
situation has been deemed unsalvageable and of course, what the situation is. 

This allows for [bold][color=#1E4F19]Central Command[/bold][/color] to be aware of 
the situation on-board the station, and to prepare their Evacuation Pod area, as well as the Emergency Shuttle area accordingly. 
You then must wait at most five minutes for a response from [bold][color=#1E4F19]Central Command[/bold][/color]. 
- If no response is given, explicit approval is assumed to have been given to proceed.
- [bold][color=violet]CFA Quarantine Protocols[/bold][/color] bypass the requirement to wait for [bold][color=#1E4F19]Central Command[/bold][/color] approval, as they cannot deny it.

##Step Four - 
A general announcement will need to be made explaining [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color]’s intent to detonate the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color]
to allow crew to get to a safe location that is resistant to the effects of the nuclear blast, or to board escape pods.
- A [bold][color=red]Hostile Occupying Force[/bold][/color] being the reason for detonation bypasses this requirement.
- If following [bold][color=violet]CFA Quarantine Protocols[/bold][/color], they demand that the Evacuation Shuttle be called before the announcement. 

It is recommended to only announce intent to detonate the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] when you are able to proceed with the detonation itself, not before then.

##Step Five - 
[bold][color=#e6b363]The Captain[/bold][/color] and [bold][color=#DB9D3B]The Head of Security[/bold][/color] may proceed with detonating the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] and once it is activated, 
they must remain on station until the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] is detonated to ensure complete and utter destruction of the station. 
- This does not mean it is a death sentence however, as the provided freezer in the [bold]Vault[/bold] has been explicitly manufactured to withstand the blast of the 
[bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] for this purpose.
- If the reason for detonation is a [bold][color=violet]Romerol Outbreak[/bold][/color], [bold][color=#e6b363]The Captain[/bold][/color] and [bold][color=#DB9D3B]The Head of Security[/bold][/color] do not have to stay behind, 
as the detonation of the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] is guaranteed.
- [bold][color=violet]CFA Quarantine Protocols[/bold][/color] demand that the [bold][color=darkred]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold][/color] is only activated two minutes before the Emergency Shuttle docks, to give enough time for the shuttle to escape the blast radius. 
[bold][color=red]This requirement can be waived if waiting for the Evacuation Shuttle would cause more casualties.[/bold][/color]


</Document>