<Document>
#Foreword
This book has been designed by various Security & CFA experts from Corporate and Governmental entities alike, with the hope that this will provide a straightforward guide for how to respond to a threat in a timely manner.

##Table of Contents
- [bold]Alert Levels And You[/bold]
- [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operative Protocol[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=violet]Romerol Outbreak Protocol[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=#1E90FF]Signs of Revolutionary Activity[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=red]Handling Revolutionary Activity[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=red]Xenoborg Protocol[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=red]Space Dragon Protocol[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=#1E90FF]Handling Changelings[/bold][/color]
- [bold]Blood Testing Procedures[/bold]
- [bold][color=#1E90FF]Handling Corporate Spies[/bold][/color]
- [bold]Implant Removal Procedures[/bold]
- [bold][color=#1E90FF]Ninja Protocol[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=#1E90FF]Abductor Protocol[/bold][/color]

##Alert Levels And You
Knowing when to change the Alert Level appropriately is of vital importance in responding to threats in a timely manner. Every section will speak about when it is correct, or what alert level you will need to be on to handle it but there are cases when you are not facing one specific threat and need a general guide on how to tailor your response appropriately. 

[bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color] - The level you are supposed to be on. Nothing is wrong.

See: [bold][textlink="Code Green" link="code-green"][/bold] for general procedures.

[bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] - A minor threat is onboard the station that may harm crew.
After 10 minutes in [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] without signs of a threat, or the threat that caused [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] is dealt with, you have to return to [bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color].

See: [bold][textlink="Code Blue" link="code-blue"][/bold] for general procedures.

Depending on the threat, [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] is advised to work in groups of two or more.

Examples that allow for raising to [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color];
- Murder(s)
- Sabotage, attempted or otherwise
- Confirmed Sighting of a [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] (See: [bold][color=#1E90FF]Ninja Protocol[/bold][/color])
- Confirmed Sighting of [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color] (See: [bold][color=#1E90FF]Abductor Protocol[/bold][/color])
- Signs of [bold][color=darkred]Corporate Spy[/bold][/color] activity (See: [bold][color=#1E90FF]Handling Corporate Spies[/bold][/color])
- Signs of [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] activity (See: [bold][color=#1E90FF]Handling Changelings[/bold][/color])
- Signs of [bold][color=#ff6200]USSP Infiltrators[/bold][/color] (See: [bold][color=#1E90FF]Signs of Revolutionary Activity[/bold][/color])
- Theft of Dangerous High Value items, such as the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Chief Medical Officer[/bold][/color]’s Hypospray
- Prisoner(s) Escaping from General Population or Solitary
- Kidnapping of a [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color] staff member

[bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color]- A major threat is onboard the station that threatens the entire crew.
After 10 minutes in [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] without signs of a threat, you must lower to [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color]. 

You can go straight to [bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color] if the threat has been confirmed to be eliminated.

See: [bold][textlink="Code Red" link="code-red"][/bold] for general procedures.

- Examples that allow for raising to [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color];
- Confirmed Sighting of [color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/color] (See: [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operative Protocol[/bold][/color])
- Confirmed Sighting of a [bold][color=#b52a2a]Space Dragon[/bold][/color] (See: [bold][color=red]Space Dragon Protocol[/bold][/color])
- Confirmed [bold][color=#ff6200]USSP-Led[/bold][/color] Revolution (See: [bold][color=red]Handling Revolutionary Activity[/bold][/color])
- Exceedingly dangerous [bold][color=darkred]Corporate Spy[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold]
- Evidence of Heavy Weapons being onboard the Station [bold][color=darkred](L6 SAW Machine Gun, China-Lake, M81A1 “Fissure” or a Holy Hand Grenade)[/color][/bold]

[bold][color=violet]Code Violet[/bold][/color]- A viral outbreak threatens the health of the entire crew.

See: [bold][textlink="Code Violet" link="code-violet"][/bold] for general procedures.

Only one scenario currently matters for [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color];
- Confirmed Sightings or signs of [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infection[/bold][/color] (See: [bold][color=violet]Romerol Outbreak Protocol[/bold][/color])

##Nuclear Operative Protocol
Any and all instances of the crew shouting out [bold][color=red]“NUKIES!”[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=yellow]“Hey, I just saw a blood-red pass by me..”[/bold][/color] Should be treated as if the crew is telling the truth and must be investigated, or confirmed with the AI immediately. If the member(s) of crew were lying, or joking over radio it is heavily recommended to detain them for [bold]Endangerment[/bold] (inciting mass panic can lead to injuries and even casualties) & [bold]Disturbance[/bold] (attempting to incite mass panic) as it is no joking matter.

- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=green]permitted[/color] for use for the duration of the threat.

If the worst of the worst has come to pass and there are [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] onboard your station quickly set alert level to [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] and then, acting quickly and decisively:

- [bold][color=red]Protect the Nuclear Authentication Disk Holder at all costs.[/bold][/color]
- [bold][color=brown]Fight the[/color] [color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/color] [color=brown]as a unit[/bold][/color]. [bold][color=#25739c]Corpsman[/bold][/color] should be focusing on keeping [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] in the fight, [bold][color=lightblue]Brigmedic[/bold][/color] should be in the backline treating critically wounded. [bold]Prevent critical condition [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] Personnel from getting captured by the [color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color].
- [bold][color=brown]Do not bunch together[/bold][/color]. While it may be tempting to fill up a corridor with [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] personnel, the [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] have access to high yield explosives that will flatten an entire department.
- [bold][color=brown]Utilize your surroundings to your advantage, maintain special awareness[/bold][/color]. A [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operative[/bold][/color] standing right next to a welding fuel tank is one less [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operative[/bold][/color] to deal with. A closed firelock with an [bold]Energy Based Weapon[/bold] is an opportunity. Assign [bold][color=#004d75][bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] Officers[/bold][/color] to watch potential flanking routes as well.
- [bold][color=brown]Flanking is effective[/bold][/color]. Several [bold][color=#004d75][bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] Officers[/bold][/color] suddenly bursting through a maintenance hallway whilst the [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] are distracted fighting the main force may provide enough of an element of surprise to eliminate them.

###War Declaration 
If the threat is more delayed, or you know ahead of time that they are coming like a [bold][color=black]Declaration of War[/bold][/color], then there are several preparations you can undertake to make the upcoming battle more in your favor.

- [bold][color=pink]Fax for Gamma Armory & Alert Level Gamma[/bold][/color] - This is the most important, and first step you should take if you are aware of a [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operative[/bold][/color] attack in advance. [bold][color=#1E4F19]Central Command[/bold][/color] will be all too happy to provide it in the face of potential station destruction. Make sure to state the nature of the threat, and the reason for requesting the armory.
- [bold][color=brown]Arm [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color], then the Crew[/bold][/color] - If they’re bold enough to declare their intentions, they are going to bring the firepower to back it up. [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] will not be enough to defend the station alone. A [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/bold][/color] or a [bold][color=darkred]Corporate Spy[/bold][/color] potentially getting a longarm and having to deal with that situation later outweighs the risk of the entire station being lost because the crew were defenseless.
- [bold][color=brown]Give[/color] [color=orange]Engineering Access[/color] [color=brown]to all of [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color][/bold][/color] - Whilst firelocks were designed to prevent casualties in dangerous situations, the last thing anyone fighting [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] needs is getting stuck on the wrong side of a firelock. By having [bold][color=orange]Engineering Access[/color]/[bold] it prevents such a scenario happening, and also gives [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] emergency access to [bold][color=orange]Engineering[/color][/bold] in the event the [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] attempt to go after the power-source of the station, which is also likely.
- [bold][color=brown]Fortify the Station[/bold][/color] - Get [bold][color=orange]Engineering[/color][/bold] to build any kind of barricades they can, glass, wooden, door, it doesn’t matter what specifically. Any barricades that slow down the movement of [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] throughout the station is a good barricade. Just ensure that crew can pass through these barricades as well, you don’t want people getting trapped in a situation like this.
- [bold][color=red]Do not allow the Nuclear Authentication Disk Holder to trap themselves[/bold][/color] - A common reaction to a dangerous situation is to hide in the area you think will be the most safe. This is generally the Bridge for the holder, which is the worst thing they can do because most Corporate Stations, to keep the area secure and harder to break into, [bold][color=red]have the Bridge be a dead end[/bold][/color]. While it may seem counterintuitive, it is much better to be constantly running around the station as it not only prevents getting cornered, but also keeps the [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operative[/bold][/color] on the move instead of heading for one particular area. In the same vein;
- [bold][color=brown]Do not be afraid to take the Nuclear Authentication Disk off of the Holder[/bold][/color] - In mockup training scenarios it has been proven time and time again [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] will not take action against the [bold]Nuclear Authentication Disk Holder[/bold], even if their actions directly endanger the station. [bold][color=#e6b363]Captains[/bold][/color] will often feel obligated to defend their station, even though they are typically the holder of the disk. This will make capturing the disk by the [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] fairly straightforwards, as fighting on the frontlines with the disk is all but hand-delivering it to them.

If the [bold][color=#e6b363]Captain[/bold][/color] or [bold]Nuclear Authentication Disk Holder[/bold] is fighting with the disk, remove it from them and give the disk to a trusted individual that will stay away from the [bold][color=red]Nuclear Operatives[/bold][/color] to the best of their ability.

##Romerol Outbreak Protocol
This section is co-authored by officials at the Concord Frontier Authority, or CFA.

Detection of a [bold][color=violet]Romerol Outbreak[/bold][/color] is fairly straightforward. If there are dead individuals still walking around the station with homicidal tendencies, you have an outbreak. 

[bold][color=violet]Code Violet[/bold][/color] must be declared as soon as possible. It may be escalated to [bold][color=pink]Code Gamma[/bold][/color] if mass crew non-compliance with Quarantine Protocols is observed.

- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=green]permitted[/color] for use for the duration of the threat.

###Quarantine Protocols
Upon detection of a [bold][color=violet]Romerol Outbreak[/bold][/color] onboard the station, all shuttles attempting to dock to the station or leave the station must be denied by the Corporate Station. [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] of the Corporate Station in question is given the authority to [bold][color=red]shoot down ships that refuse to listen to these orders[/bold][/color] if necessary.

A station-wide announcement must also be made declaring the Corporate Station is under CFA mandated quarantine and that no individual is allowed to attempt to leave or enter the Corporate Station through Shuttles or EVA, and [bold][color=red]any means necessary[/bold][/color] will be taken to prevent that. If the infection continues to spread at an alarming rate, a second announcement stating all crew must shelter in place within their department must be made.

[bold]Refusal to Comply[/bold] and [bold]Endangerment[/bold] are applicable crimes for charging individuals that ignore these orders, ontop of any other law(s) they may have broken. Individuals attempting to hide their [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infection[/bold][/color] can be considered an act of [bold][color=darkred]Treason[/bold][/color] and even [bold][color=red]Terrorism[/bold][/color] if evidence is established that they were doing so with the intent to spread the [bold][color=violet]Romerol Outbreak[/bold][/color].

Exceptions are granted for [bold][color=orange]Engineers[/color][/bold] and [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] to perform their jobs, but every instance of exiting the station must be logged and written down on paper with the relevant Department Head’s stamp for record-keeping. This may be done afterwards if it is an emergency, such as a catastrophic hull breach, or a ship attempting to breach quarantine.

Infected, but not yet dead individuals must be held in individual medical quarantine cells and regularly given doses of Dylovene, Diphenhydramine or Tricordrazine while resting as much as possible to delay succumbing to the [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infection[/bold][/color] until a Cure can be made.

If control is lost over the station, or the majority of the station has been infected with [bold][color=violet]Romerol[/bold][/color], the [bold][color=#e6b363]Captain[/bold][/color] and Head of [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color], or if not applicable, any surviving member of [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color] must proceed with the [bold][color=darkred]Prometheus Protocol[/bold][/color].

###Romerol Procedures
[bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] must be in full biohazardous suits at all times while handling [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infected Individuals[/bold][/color] unless they are immune to the virus through the Vaccine or are Mechanical Individuals. Riot Armor and Hardsuits with internals are an acceptable replacement if there are not enough biohazardous suits to go around, but it is heavily recommended they do not get within [bold][color=red]biting distance[/bold][/color] of the [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infected Individuals[/bold][/color].

Defenses such as [bold]Electric Fences[/bold], or [bold]Superheated Corridors[/bold] are highly effective against [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infected Individuals[/bold][/color], and may be employed by [bold][color=orange]Engineering[/color][/bold] and [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] to slow down spread of the infection.

Operation of [bold][bold][color=#004d75]Security Checkpoints[/bold][/color] and regularly checking Corporate Station EVA Exits become mandatory to maintain quarantine and constructing makeshift checkpoints around the station to check for infection is heavily recommended.

If the [bold][color=darkred]Prometheus Protocol[/bold][/color] is enacted, [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] must shift defensive priorities to ensure the Evacuation Shuttle does not get overrun with [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infected Individuals[/bold][/color]. Screening for Evacuation must be done as soon as the shuttle is called, and a limit of one individual passing through the [bold][bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] Evacuation Checkpoint[/bold] must be enforced, [bold][color=red]at gunpoint[/bold][/color] if necessary.

It is the [bold][color=#25739c]Security Medical Staff’s job[/bold][/color], or if unavailable, a [bold][color=#004d75][bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] Officer[/bold][/color] with a Medical Scanner to check every individual being processed through the Evacuation Checkpoint for Symptoms of [bold][color=violet]Romerol Infection[/bold][/color], which is their blood steadily rising in accumulated toxins with no discernable cause.

[bold][color=red]Any Infected but not Dead individuals must be denied entry into the Evacuation Shuttle[/bold][/color] and instead redirected to Evacuation Pods. Only uninfected individuals may be allowed into the evacuation area, due to the danger of infecting the entire crew being too high.

##Signs of Revolutionary Activity
[bold]This section is color coded with levels of severity, and will therefore lack other color codes asides from those listed below;[/bold]

[color=#ff6200]Orange is Concering[/color]

[color=#f00000]Red is Alarming[/color]

[bold][color=#f00000]Bold Red is act now![/color][/bold]

While flashes are a known method for USSP brainwashing, this does not directly mean an individual [color=#ff6200]using flashes against another individual[/color] is a USSP infiltrator, as it may be a simple assault case. Perhaps over a disagreement about who gets the insulated gloves among tiders. You will need to observe the behaviors of the flashed individual(s) closely, do they:

- [color=#ff6200]Experience personality changes[/color]

This may be as innocuous as not liking their favorite food after the event, or as alarming as becoming outwardly hostile towards command staff. Insulting them, threatening physical violence, and of course acting on those threats.

- [color=#ff6200]Behave oddly[/color]

This ranges anywhere from suddenly gaining a desire for the manufacture and distribution of weapons, or perhaps acquiring one for oneself to requesting odd items not related to their typical job duties, such as a member of medical staff asking Science for circuit printers or a member of engineering asking Medical for a large quantity of medicinal or toxic chemicals.

This is not a conclusive list and can also include: Allowing personnel without proper access to their department inside without question, such as a member of service being allowed into the engineering area without cause, among many other strange, out of place behaviors.

- [color=#ff6200]Spout anti-corporate propaganda[/color]

This can be as simple as asking how NanoTransen’s working conditions are and suggesting better, USSP aligned workplaces or outright suggesting they would be better off without the current leadership of the station.

- [color=#f00000]Gather and act in groups[/color]

Groups of flashed individuals gathering together who have no relation to eachother outside of being assaulted with a flash, especially around the individual who allegedly assaulted them with a flash is the most alarming sign of revolutionary activity. Brainwashed revolutionaries will naturally attempt to plot the takeover of the station for the USSP together, and coordinate in groups lead by the USSP agent if possible.

###Revolutionary Proceedures

Flashed individuals experiencing one or more of these symptoms may be grounds for forcing a mindshield implant upon them as well as grounds for the subsequent capture and mindshield testing for the suspected USSP agent, up to the discretion of both the Head of Security and Magistrate, or Captain if the Magistrate is not available. 

[bold]The Head of Security alone cannot decide to force a mindshield on an non-violent individual, it must be with the approval of the Magistrate, or [bold][color=#e6b363]Captain[/bold][/color] if they are not available. Doing so without the Magistrate or Captain’s approval is a violation of an individual’s spacelaw rights[/bold]

However, if the individual is:

- [color=#ff6200]Violent[/color]

Has performed any red color coded crimes (eg. minor assault, major assault, attempted murder)
- [color=#f00000]Hostile to command [/color]

Attempting to take the life of command, regardless if they succeed
- [bold][color=#f00000]Directly spouting revolutionary phrases[/color][/bold]

[color=#f00000]"Glory to the USSP”[/color], [color=#f00000]“Revolt!”[/color], [color=#f00000]“Revolution!”[/color] or other variations thereof.

The Head of Security may proceed with forced mindshielding without needing the approval of the Captain or Magistrate, as that is evidence enough.

###Methods to confirm a USSP led revolution is occurring
- [color=#f00000]Mindshield implant failing/breaking[/color]

This is direct evidence of the individual being a USSP agent, and must be executed as soon as possible within the bounds of space law*. Emergency executions may be performed by the Head of Security with the Magistrate, or Captain** if they are not available as witness if the station has already fallen into active warfare*** with revolutionaries and non-revolutionaries. 

*To lawfully execute a confirmed head revolutionary, you must print out, or have on the same paper, a DNR form and Execution form signed and stamped by the Head of Security.

**If both the Captain and Magistrate are unavailable, dead, or otherwise unreachable any member of command will do. If the Head of Security is the only member of command not incapacitated they may carry forwards with the execution by themself.

***Defined as mass combat taking place across the station between those converted and not-converted/mindshieldied.

- [color=#f00000]Mindshield implant de-converting an individual[/color]

This is direct confirmation that there is a USSP agent running around on the station brainwashing members of the crew and as such an active revolution is confirmed to be taking place. Action must be taken promptly to locate and get rid of the agent before it is too late.

- [bold][color=#f00000]Redspace Rifts being confirmed or announced[/color][/bold]

[color=#f00000]Redspace[/color] is a dead giveaway that there is an active revolution onboard the station, and is grounds for immediate [bold]Code Gamma[/bold] as it signals a large population of the station has fallen to mind-control.

##Handling Revolutionary Activity
Once a Revolution is confirmed [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] 
must be called for the duration of the threat, or even 
[bold][color=pink]Code Gamma[/bold][/color] if the situation is dire. 

- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=red]not permitted[/color] 
for use during the duration of this threat, unless a [bold][color=red]Redspace Rift[/bold][/color] has been opened, or [bold][color=pink]Code Gamma[/bold][/color] has been declared.

[bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] must act quickly to prevent more individuals from getting brainwashed while also searching for the 
[bold][color=#ff6200]USSP agent(s)[/bold][/color], several methods will be listed below;

###Sunglasses / Security Glasses / Welding Masks
These protect individuals from the brainwashing effects of [bold]flashes[/bold], 
although it comes with the obvious caveat that they can easily be forcefully removed. 
Regardless, it is better than nothing, though caution is advised around handing out [bold][color=#004d75]Security Glasses[/bold][/color] specifically 
as it reveals the status of mindshields to Revolutionaries if it falls into the wrong hands.

###Mindshields
In a perfect world you would simply be able to mindshield everyone to prevent them from being brainwashed. 
In reality however, this is not something you can do as the station’s supply of mindshields is extremely limited, 
and further shipments will likely be disrupted by revolutionaries. It heavily advised [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] saves their mindshield supply for finding out who the 
[bold][color=#ff6200]USSP agent(s)[/bold][/color] are, 
as killing them deconverts the unfortunate individuals who were brainwashed directly by them.

###Moving Vulnerable Individuals Into Secure Areas
Another more simple method is simply gathering the crew and forcefully relocating them, 
as is your right as [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] on [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] into secure areas where they are not at risk of being converted. 
If this is not possible, posting [bold][color=#004d75]Security Staff[/bold][/color] in certain areas that need departmental staff to continue vital function of the station like 
[bold][color=#527A87]Medical[/bold][/color] will work as well.

If at any time a [bold][color=red]Redspace Rift[/bold][/color] is spotted, announced, or detected by the Station’s network, 
Security must drop efforts of protecting individuals from brainwashing and focus on taking out the 
[bold][color=red]Redspace Rift[/bold][/color] as well as any Revolutionaries in the area.

[bold][color=red]Any individual that is not mindshielded within 
the area of the rift will automatically be assumed to be an active, hostile revolutionary.[/bold][/color]

Lastly, [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] must make a good-faith effort to prevent 
Revolutionaries from rotting by acquiring body-bags or 
freezers to put the dead Revolutionaries inside. It is not their fault they have been brainwashed, 
and while having members of your department slain by these individuals will no doubt sting, 
they cannot be held responsible for their actions while under mind control. 
- [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] is not obligated to revive Revolutionaries without Mindshields.

##Xenoborg Protocol
On detection of [bold][color=#290000]Xenoborgs[/bold][/color], through [bold][color=#e6b363]AI[/bold][/color] confirmation, 
crew reports or direct [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] confirmation the station should 
immediately be raised to [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] until the threat is dealt with. 
- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=green]permitted[/color] for use for the duration of the threat.
- You may also additionally fax for [bold][color=pink]Psi Armory[/bold][/color] 
from [bold][color=#1E4F19]Central Command[/bold][/color] if the [bold][color=#290000]Xenoborg[/bold][/color] situation gets dire enough, 
but you are still expected to try and handle it yourself first before asking for support. 

[bold][color=#290000]Xenoborgs[/bold][/color] are only known to utilize high-power laser weaponry. 
For that reason, armor that deflects lasers or absorbs them entirely is advised to be utilized when possible. 
Additionally, [bold][color=#290000]Xenoborgs[/bold][/color] employ the use of “perfect-camoflauge” drones, [bold][color=red]if you hear movement but do not see it[/bold][/color], 
you are likely in grave danger and the advised course of action is to fire your longarm in the 
direction of what is making the noise.

Any and all [bold][color=#290000]Xenoborgs[/bold][/color] must be captured if possible, and then destroyed for the pinpointer piece they contain within. 
You need around 4 pinpointer pieces, which means 4 [bold][color=#290000]Xenoborgs[/bold][/color] captured and destroyed total to be able to hunt down the [bold][color=#290000]Mothership[/bold][/color]. 
- The [bold][color=#290000]Xenoborgs[/bold][/color] are aware of this, so they will be avoiding capture as much as possible. 
[bold]Do not let them escape once you have them in your sights.[/bold]

Once a makeshift pinpointer has been assembled, [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] may mobilize and go on the offensive to finally 
end the threat to the station, utilizing the [bold][color=#004d75]Security Shuttle[/bold][/color] to do so. 
- It is advised to leave a few members of [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] behind during this charge, to not leave the station totally defenseless.
- If a makeshift pinpointer is not able to be constructed and the threat has been going on for over an hour with 
abductions continuing to happen, [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] may use the [bold][color=#004d75]Security Shuttle[/bold][/color] as a 
battering ram to find the [bold][color=#290000]Mothership[/bold][/color] the old-fashioned way.

##Space Dragon Protocol
After confirming a report of a [bold][color=#b52a2a]Space Dragon[/bold][/color] through panicked screaming of crew, 
or the station’s automatic monitoring system picking up a surge of energy at a location which is a surefire sign of a 
[bold][color=#b52a2a]Draconic Rift[/bold][/color], the recommended course of action is changing the alert level to [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] 
and arming [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] to eliminate the threat.
- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=green]permitted[/color] for use for the duration of the threat, although it is not recommended due to the 
[bold][color=#b52a2a]Space Dragon[/bold][/color]’s agility and the [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color]’s lack thereof.

[bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] should not fight the [bold][color=#b52a2a]Space Dragon[/bold][/color] alone, as they may simply end up as its next meal. 
It is therefore heavily advised to fight the [bold][color=#b52a2a]Space Dragon[/bold][/color] together as a unit to be able to catch and drag away any 
members of [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] that may be knocked into critical condition by the [bold][color=#b52a2a]Space Dragon[/bold][/color].

##Handling Changelings
Evidence of one or more [bold][color=cyan]Changelings[/color][/bold] having snuck onto station generally revolve around [color=yellow]the mysterious 
disappearances of one or more crewmembers[/color], [color=red]strange ferrous cyan puddles lying 
around in maintenance, crewmembers strangely becoming mute from some type of 
sting[/color] or of course, the most alarming and revealing of all; [bold][color=red]Hollow Bodies.[/bold][/color]

For handling testing, see: [bold]Blood Testing Procedures[/bold]
- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=red]not permitted[/color] for use against [bold][color=cyan]Changelings[/color][/bold] 
due to the CFA’s strict permit regulations unless a [bold][color=cyan]Changeling(s)[/color][/bold] has proven themselves to be a credible threat 
to the station at large, such as eliminating a significant number of 
[bold][color=#004d75]Security Forces[/bold][/color] or multiple (3+) members of [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color].

Once [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] activity has been confirmed, through discovery of [color=cyan]ferrous cyan puddles[/color] or [bold][color=red]hollow bodies[/bold][/color], 
the recommended course of action is escalating the alert level to [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] and 
having [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] patrol the station in pairs, as alone a [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] can be quite lethal to an 
unsuspecting [bold][color=#004d75]Security Officer[/bold][/color]. 

Any and all hollow bodies should be brought to [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] for further examination 
by the [bold][color=#25739c]Security Medical Staff[/bold][/color], and then once they are finished brought to 
[bold][color=#527A87]Medical[/bold][/color] for revival.

Marking a hollow individual as “Hollow” and then flagging as “Arrest On Sight” through the Criminal Records Computer 
is often an excellent way of catching unsuspecting [bold][color=cyan]Changelings[/color][/bold], 
though do keep in mind that [bold][color=#527A87]Medical[/bold][/color] will eventually revive the original victim, 
so double check upon capture if the victim has been revived or not. 

[bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] can be active indefinitely until a confirmed kill of a known active [bold][color=cyan]Changeling(s)[/color][/bold]. 
[bold]Lack of activity in this case, does not mean they are gone.[/bold]

##Blood Testing Procedures
If you suspect someone of being a [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] and need to test their blood, you must ensure that there is;

###Proof or Reasonable Cause
[bold]Proof[/bold] can come in many forms, but generally, a [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] using one of their inherent abilities right in front of you is 
often evidence enough, be it shapeshifting into something else or screaming loud enough to fry nearby electronics.
- DNA evidence is also a good method to prove [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] activity, 
but most [bold][color=cyan]Changelings[/color][/bold] are aware of this and do not leave that behind or simply change 
forms to avoid tracking, so it is not the most reliable method as to figuring out if someone is a [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] or not.

For [bold]Reasonable Cause[/bold], a bloodtest may be performed on [color=red]violent individuals[/color], or [color=red]individuals that have committed violent crimes[/color] on 
[bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] or higher.
- More than one identical individual roaming the station also constitutes for [bold]Reasonable Cause[/bold] as if there are two Johns 
on shift but only one on manifest, 
this could very well be evidence of [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] activities, but it may also be a [bold]Paradox Clone[/bold]. 
Regardless, a simple blood-test in this situation is valid to either verify the [bold]Paradox Clone[/bold]’s existence, 
or the fact that they are a [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold].

With [bold]Reasonable Cause[/bold], or [bold]Proof[/bold], established you may proceed with detainment of the individual. 
And that is correct, [bold]Detainment[/bold]. Even if the individual is willing to subject themselves to a blood-test, 
it is heavily recommended that you detain them regardless as [bold][color=cyan]Changelings[/color][/bold] are known manipulators, 
and may simply be getting you in an un-ideal position to try and escape. 

Restraining them makes them harder for that to achieve, but not impossible due to their ability to escape restraints on demand. 
For that reason, it is also heavily recommended you bring back-up to a blood-test, 
especially if you are an individual affected by electro-magnetic pulses. However, to perform the test itself you need;

###The Chief Medical Officer or Security Medical Staff Present
A trustworthy medical professional such as the [bold][color=lightblue]Brigmedic[/bold][/color], [bold][color=#25739c]Corpsman[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Chief Medical Officer[/bold][/color] is 
required for the test to be conducted so it can be cataloged and performed properly. 
- The attending [bold][color=#527A87]Medical Staff[/bold][/color], be it the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]CMO[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=#25739c]Security Medical[/bold][/color] are expected to jot down 
and verify with a stamp the results on paper regardless if successful or not, for CFA legal procedures.

Once the test is concluded you may continue with the release of the non-changeling individual, or burning of the [bold][color=cyan]Changeling[/color][/bold] individual. 

##Handling Corporate Spies
Evidence of [bold][color=darkred]Corporate Spy[/bold][/color] operating on station, through finding a large amount of [bold][color=darkred]Syndicate Contraband[/bold][/color], Explosive Devices going off, 
seemingly targeted murders of [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color], or sabotage of a department allows for the raising of the alert level from [bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color] to [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color]
and in certain cases, [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] if hostile activity is rampant. 

For implant removal, see: [bold]Implant Removal Procedures[/bold]

Generally only the death of the [bold][color=#e6b363]Captain[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Head of Security[/bold][/color] is cause for immediate alarm and even raising of alert level to [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] if certain valuable items, 
like their self-recharging firearms, or the [bold][color=red]Nuclear Authentication Disk[/bold][/color] is stolen as it would pose an immediate and credible threat to the station at large. 
The death of other [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color] staff is worrisome as well, but only worth [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] as there would not be an immediate threat to the station. 
- [bold][color=#DB9D3B]The Chief Engineer[/bold][/color] or the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Research Director[/bold][/color] dying is not cause for immediate alarm, as it may simply be an accident as it often happens in their line of work.

The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is not permitted for use against [bold][color=darkred]Corporate Spies[/bold][/color] due to the CFA’s strict permit regulations unless a 
[bold][color=darkred]Corporate Spy[/bold][/color] has proven themselves to be a credible threat to the station at large, such as [color=red]eliminating[/color] a significant number of [bold][color=#004d75]Security Forces[/bold][/color], 
[bold][color=red]attempting to arm the Onboard Nuclear Warhead[/bold][/color] or having access to Heavy Weaponry such as the [bold][color=darkred]L6 SAW Machine Gun, China-Lake, M81A1 “Fissure” or a Holy Hand Grenade[/bold][/color]. 
- Extreme caution is recommended for handling an individual with the [bold][color=darkred]Holy Hand Grenade[/bold][/color], as all it takes is a single pull of a pin 
to take an entire department out of commission.

If [bold]Cyborgs[/bold] have been compromised by [bold][color=darkred]Corporate Spies[/bold][/color], a thorough investigation of every [bold]Cyborg Chassis[/bold] suspected to be 
compromised is recommended through working with the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Research Director[/bold][/color] to check if their brain is able to be removed from the 
chassis by the [bold]Robotics Control Console[/bold], including searching for illegal modules in their chassis that may have been given to them.

##Implant Removal Procedures
Removing an implant can only be done by a medical professional, either from the [bold][color=#527A87]Medical[/bold][/color] department or 
by [bold][color=#25739c]Security Medical Staff[/bold][/color], as regular [bold][color=#004d75]Security Officers[/bold][/color] are not medically qualified to perform such a delicate procedure. 
- If this is ignored, the officer in question, or if they were ordered to do it, the individual who ordered them, will be liable for [bold]Endangerment[/bold], 
regardless if the officer succeeds at the task or not.

If an implant is found, and more is suspected within the individual but not verified, 
[bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] may attempt to search for the other implants. However, if they harm the suspect by being incorrect, 
they can be held responsible for [bold]Minor Assault[/bold] and must stop further attempts.

The [bold][color=#527A87]Medical[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=#25739c]Security Medical[/bold][/color] Staff that has performed the procedure will then need to write down the results of the 
extraction regardless if it succeeds or not, and then verify it with either the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Chief Medical Officer[/bold][/color]’s stamp, or in the case of [bold][color=#25739c]Security Medical[/bold][/color], 
their own company-provided stamps.

##Ninja Protocol
Confirmation of [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja Activity[/bold][/color] can [bold]usually*[/bold] be boiled down to [bold][color=red]“Invisible thing running through 'Location'!”[/bold][/color] by random members of the crew. [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] is to operate under the assumption the crew is telling the truth if several (2+) reports of a similar nature are made as obtaining a visual confirmation of a [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] is quite difficult. 
- [bold]*[/bold]Not all reports of invisible things running around may be a [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color], however. 
[bold][color=#360000]Stealth Xenoborgs[/bold][/color], 
[bold][color=darkred]Invisible Boxes[/bold][/color] and 
[bold][color=purple]Anomaly Infected[/bold][/color] members of the crew may also create these calls.

Once reported, or visually confirmed by [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=#e6b363]Command[/bold][/color] the alert level may be escalated to [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color]. 
- A particularly hostile [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] may be worthy of [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color].

[bold][color=#DB9D3B]The Head of Security[/bold][/color] or [bold][color=#00527d]Warden[/bold][/color] are advised to hand out basic longarm permits and Riot Armor to [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] so the [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] can more effectively be dealt with.

- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=red]not permitted[/color] for use due to the Ninja being a 
[bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] threat. Even if a particular [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] 
is a large enough threat to trigger [bold][color=red]Code Red[/bold][/color] it is still not permitted due to the fact 
that they can simply send a disabling shock straight through the thick armor plating and cause the loss of the 
[color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color], as well as the M492.

[bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] should not be attempting to take on a [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] 
alone, nor even in groups of two. Groups of three or more are recommended when hunting for the 
[bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color], as the [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] is capable of 
delivering electromagnetic shocks through their gloves that temporarily disable anyone they touch. Likewise, 
they are also capable of setting off electromagnetic pulses that can disable nearby electrical equipment, 
or any [bold][color=#004d75]Security Officer[/bold][/color] weak to such things.

- At least one member of [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] should be stationed in Science around the entrance to the 
Server Room to protect the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Research Director[/bold][/color]’s research from theft.

Shotguns loaded with [bold]Incendiary Rounds[/bold] are the most effective way to take down a [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color], due to the sheer damage it can output in close encounters. 
Other longarms such as Rifles or SMGs are less effective due to the fact most combat with a [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] will take place within close quarters, 
putting the [bold][color=#004d75]Security Officer[/bold][/color] at great risk for being disabled by the [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color].

Alternatively, [bold][color=limegreen]Ninjas[/bold][/color] typically have secondary goals assigned to them by the [bold][color=limegreen]Spider Clan[/bold][/color] that may 
be acceptable to perform over stealing the [bold][color=#DB9D3B]Research Director[/bold][/color]’s research. Should the station wish to negotiate 
with a particularly elusive [bold][color=limegreen]Ninja[/bold][/color] to perform those goals over the theft of [bold]Company Research[/bold], it is acceptable 
so long as it does not disrupt the ongoing shift too much.

##Abductor Protocol
Due to their advanced technology, [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] cannot realistically do much to stop abductions at its source, 
such as hunting down the ship allowing them to perform the abductions as it will likely not even be remotely near the station, as such the only chance [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] really has is trying to stop abductions happening nearby. It is advised to plant one or more 
[bold][color=#004d75]Security Officers[/bold][/color] in every department, with [bold]Departmental Access[/bold] to that department so they can intervene in any and all abduction attempts.

Once [bold][color=purple]Abductor Activity[/bold][/color] has been confirmed, through strange purple wisps that their teleportation leaves behind, 
the iconic sound of the stunprod being used or visually identifying an [bold][color=purple]Abductor[/bold][/color], 
it is recommended to escalate to [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color]
- The [color=#004d75]Security Juggernaut[/color] is [color=red]not appropriate[/color] for use against [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color], due to them being a [bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] threat at most. 
It is also far too slow to provide any reasonable performance against fast moving [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color] capable of teleportation.

[bold][color=#DB9D3B]The Head of Security[/bold][/color] should make a station-wide announcement that no member of crew should be walking around alone or in maintenance, and to stay within view of 
[bold][color=#004d75]Security Officers[/bold][/color] as [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color] prefer to not fight and go after isolated, lone targets that will not have a chance to scream. 

If there are other threats, [bold][color=#004d75]Security[/bold][/color] should prioritise those threats over the [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color], as while they are annoying they do not pose a real threat 
to station crew, outside of potential mental harm that may be inflicted from being abducted and having an alien organ replace their own.

A simpler option of course, is to simply negotiate with the [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color]. 
They wish to perform experiments, there are likely some members of the crew fascinated with the idea of having strange alien organs that do irregular things, 
it is almost perfect for conducting a mutual experiment on how these organs perform. 
- If the [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color] agree to only abduct consenting crew, the alert level may be lowered to [bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color].

[bold][color=#1E90FF]Code Blue[/bold][/color] can be active indefinitely until the [bold][color=purple]Abductors[/bold][/color] have been confirmed to be eliminated, or have been talked into operating on willing crew.
</Document>
