<Document>
# Blueshield Officer
The Blueshield Officer reports directly to Central Command (CC), as opposed to the average crewmember and therefore cannot be commanded by anyone on station, including Station Management (SM) and Station Command (SC) to do anything. Any orders from CC override everything else including their own job.

The job of the Blueshield Officer revolves around the protection of both SC and SM personnel, however if they cannot protect both at the same time, individuals at the top of the Station Management hierarchy, or, Upper Management is to be prioritized above all else, with the protection hierarchy defined below.

# Upper Management
1. NanoTrasen Representative (NTR)

2. Magistrate

# Station Command
3. All members of Command

# Lower Management
4. Affairs Official (Both NT-HQ and CFA)

The NTR is always top priority regardless of the situation. If the Blueshield Officer fails to protect the NTR, they have failed their job.

It is ultimately up to the Blueshield Officer to decide who to prioritize in Station Command, depending on context and the current circumstances. However, it’s recommended that the Captain take priority in times of emergency, and the Head of Security to be left to their own devices given their self-defense capabilities.

# Procedures

1. The Blueshield Officer may ignore Space Law only when actively performing actions to protect their charge, and must have proper justification to do so. “The tider sneezed on my charge” is not a valid justification and the Blueshield Officer will be subject to criminal punishment if they act like this.

2. The Blueshield Officer is subject to the same restrictions on Armory Weapons as a Security Officer and may not take any weapons from Armory without a permit on code Blue, but may arm without a permit on code Red, Violet or Gamma.

3. The Blueshield Officer is not restricted in the weapons they may carry, so long as armory weapons stay with the Warden's issued permit. However, their weapons should not be visible and must be holstered or placed in a bag or pocket on any alert level below Red.

4. The Blueshield Officer should focus on protecting their charge, and should not be pursuing potential threats to the detriment of their charge**
- *Unless the threat is station-ending, which is defined in Nuclear Operative Procedures.
- **Detriment of Charge is defined as abandoning your Charge at any point to pursue the threat. You may scare them off, but not chase.


5. The Blueshield Officer cannot interfere with any lawful arrest, regardless of the position of the individual in question.


</Document> 