<Document>
# General Procedures
This section of SoP is dedicated to what ALL members of station management should do in specific situations.

# Safety Protocol
1. As a member of Station Management, your safety is paramount. On Code Red or above, all members of Station Management should seek shelter in Command or their respective assigned departments, with exception of the BSO who should continue their duties.

2. In the event of a Code Gamma, all members of Station Management are to communicate and gather on the bridge and await ERT support.

3. In the event of contract terminations, all members of Station Management will be escorted off station by a NanoTrasen marine squad.

# Nuclear Operative Procedures
This exists solely to handle NOTs (Nuclear Operative Threats). The Blueshield Officer during this time of crises may take any and all methods (including forcefully restraining SMs) to ensure the safety and continued life of SMs, as well as the integrity of the station at large.

SM (Station Management) are defined as:
- The NanoTrasen Representative
- Magistrate
- Affairs Officers

1. In the event of NOTs, all SMs are to report to the bridge for escort by the Blueshield Officer to the designated Safe Location which is the Tech Vault. However, if the Tech Vault is not viable, or compromised for some reason it is ultimately up to the judgement of the Blueshield Officer as to what would be a Safe Location. Regardless, once there the SMs may not leave the location until the threat is over unless the location becomes compromised.

-If the Safe Location does not have access to a Fax or Document printer, one is to be provided if possible to allow the flow of communication to Central Command.

- The BSO is to NOT bring the Nuclear Authentication Disk to the Safe Location, as that makes it a prime target for NOTs. In other words, Captain (or the current holder of the Nuclear Authentication DIsk) is not allowed to come along.

- Bridge, Security, Medical & Vault are not considered Safe Locations.

2. The Blueshield Officer must immediately drop what they are doing on discovery of NOTs to gather SMs into a Safe Location, and may only assist security with combating the NTOs when the SMs are safe. Not before.

3. SMs may be given firearms and equipment to protect themselves in the event the Safe Location is compromised, so long as it is not to the detriment of Security’s ability to fend off NOTs.

4. The Blueshield Officer may not at any time attempt to challenge NOTs by themselves, and may only fight NOTs with the company of reinforcements (Security or Head of Security)

- This includes suspected Lone Operatives, as there is no way to verify they are working alone.
- If security is incapacitated, the BSO is free to engage without support to prevent the detonation of the Onboard Nuclear Device*
*If conditions of rule 5 is met

5. If the Onboard Nuclear Device is armed, the Blueshield Officer MUST retrieve the SMs from the Safe Location and bring them off-station if a shuttle is available. If all possible shuttles have been destroyed or otherwise rendered inoperable, the Blueshield Officer may attempt a Defusal.

- The Blueshield Officer may choose to stay behind on station to prevent detonation of the Onboard Nuclear Device, so long as the SMs are off-station.

6. If the Safe Location at any time is compromised by active hostiles, the Blueshield Officer must stop whatever they are doing, including fighting NOTs to protect SMs.

- An active hostile is defined as a person with the intent to kill the SMs. Not a curious Passenger.

</Document> 