<Document>
# Metashield
This can also be viewed on the FarHorizons Wiki

[bold]Supporting Documents[/bold]
- [bold][textlink="The Head Of Security Almanac" link="security-almanac"][/bold]

While not a necessary read, it helps [bold]Security[/bold] act within in-character logic. Anything within is considered [bold][color=#f00000]Secure Information[/color][/bold].

## What is the “Metashield”?
It’s an Out Of Character (OOC) system to help guide your reactions to information you may come across in a round, or remember from previous rounds. Generally you have a certain amount of knowledge you start out with, depending on your profession, which will be built upon with your in-round experiences.

[bold]Once you have witnessed something, you may remember it indefinitely, with a slight exception[/bold]

That exception being “John was working for the Syndicate last shift” - This is a gameplay limitation, if you were actually caught as an antagonist you would no longer be employed with your respective company (NT, GSL, NS, ect) so you may in-character remember that John did something to make you angry, or lower your opinion of them, but not that they were specifically working as an agent of the respective traitor faction.

Examples for following this rule:
- Instead of, “John Killed me for his objective as a syndicate traitor” 
You would instead think, “John killed me over a disagreement, that asshole!” This would be valid to keep things within continuity logic.

- If the individual was a Changeling, going “John, a changeling that looked like you killed me!” is valid, due to that information not breaking continuity logic.

The information system that will be utilized within the Metashield is broken into four parts;
- [bold][color=#ff6200]Unknown Information[/color][/bold] is explicitly Out Of Character information and cannot be utilized In-Character.
- [bold][color=#9819ff]Corporate Secrets[/color][/bold] are well-kept secrets by the corporation(s) you work for, and are only known by high-up staff of the corporation in question, such as Central Command / Syndicate High Command and Representatives of the Major Factions (NanoTrasen / NeoSol  Representative & Blue Shield / Red Sword Officer). 

Individuals who are aware of this information by default should not at any point reveal them, unless the situation is dire.

Individuals who learn of this knowledge through in-round experiences also cannot at any point reveal them publicly, as it will result in their immediate termination from the company, and even detainment of the individual in question by [bold]Security[/bold] if they continue to talk about it.


- [bold][color=#f00000]Secure Information[/color][/bold] is information collectively known by Command (AI is included in this) & Security and of course anyone who knows [bold][color=#9819ff]Corporate Secrets.[/color][/bold]

Individuals who know this information by default should not be revealing it unless the situation calls for it, as the company that they work for would rather they do not leak secure information over the public radio.

Individuals who learn of this knowledge through in-round experiences should not be talking about it over the radio or in public as it would be violating the NDA all employees have signed to be employed at their corporation and will result in Administrative Action by their respective Head of Staff that they report to. For a Head of Staff violating this rule, it would be the Captain. 

Repeated violations are grounds for termination from your position, and even your employment with the company.

- [bold][color=#0af024]Public Information[/color][/bold] is, as you might guess, knowledge that is either freely accessible over the internet or just generally known by Station Crews. There is no consequence for referencing this information, and exists mainly as material for world-building or an assist for how to react in-character for a certain situation.

To explain why you can’t just talk about information you have learned, but are not supposed to know, every employee of a corporation signs a strict NDA (Non-Disclosure Agreement) preventing them from talking about certain topics in public. This applies to [bold][color=#9819ff]Corporate Secrets[/color][/bold] & [bold][color=#f00000]Secure Information[/color][/bold] - Whispering to your friend about how [bold]Lambda Hardliners[/bold] are actually still working for NanoTrasen is fine (if you somehow learn of this), shouting it over radio for everyone to hear is not.

##Unknown Information
[color=#ff6200]Out Of Character “Meta” Information;[/color][/bold]

[bold][color=#ff6200]Current Gamemode[/color][/bold]

[bold]Ex.[/bold] Survival being voted does not mean you in-character know it is Survival, and to expect an escalating number of threats to the station.

[bold][color=#ff6200]Events you experienced as another character[/color][/bold]

[bold]Ex.[/bold] Getting killed as Jane by David and then newlifing as John, you do not have Jane’s memories and so you cannot know that David killed Jane unless it is revealed to you by someone else.

[bold][color=#ff6200]Abusing game mechanics to discover an item’s secret use[/color][/bold]

[bold]Ex.[/bold] Right clicking on a pair of chameleon clothes to find the in-game option of “Charmelon”

Your character may know of these items, but it does not mean your character knows the exact button or trigger to use them, and thus be able to find out it is in fact a piece of clothing that can be charmeloned into other clothing. The same applies to Hypopens, or any other item that attempts to look exactly like a non-secret use normal item.

Obviously if you see the secret item used in front of you or have managed to gather evidence (such as scanning clothes for chameleon fibers), you know the item is “Chameleon ” or has a secret use.

[bold][color=#ff6200]Information gained while Unconscious, Dead or Spectating.[/color][/bold]

Loss of consciousness is defined by being forcefully put to sleep, knocked into critical condition or killed. When you are in these state(s) you will not remember any information you may have seen or heard, and you will only be allowed to have vague recollection of what happened to you when you wake back up, as an example;

[color=green]“The last thing I remember was an engineer approaching me..” or “An engineer was with me..”[/color] is valid [bold]if the person is dressed up like an engineer[/bold], because going “a guy in a yellow jumpsuit and green goggles” comes to the same result for the Security Officer interviewing you. 

[bold][color=red]However[/bold][/color] if they are not dressed up like an engineer then you cannot reveal their job, and can only say vague details like “grey jumpsuit and black boots” or things along that line. 

Job Icons, if you can see them, do not count towards being able to say the name of the person’s job as you will not remember that.

You can also use common sense to vaguely figure out what happened to you, depending on if you wake up with your wounds untreated or not. Obviously, if someone shot you and you woke up with that gunshot wound untreated, you can reasonably deduce that you were shot. As an example;

[bold][color=green]“I was shot!”[/bold][/color] is vague enough and as such valid for recollection, based on inspecting your wounds.

[bold][color=red]“I was shot by a gun that fires 9mm bullets”[/bold][/color] is too specific and is not a valid thing to say. While specialized medical professionals can reasonably figure out the type of caliber you got shot with, this is sadly not a game mechanic and thus not something you, or anyone else, can say based off of inspecting your wounds alone.

If you wake up fully healed, you cannot come to this conclusion since you are not visibly hurt in any way.

[bold]You cannot reveal the name, species, or special inspect text a person may have after losing consciousness. As these are all details that you would not remember, mostly to keep it fair for the Antagonist. Just think of it as being a really fuzzy recollection for your character due to passing out.[/bold]

[bold][color=#ff6200]Metafriending & Metagrudging[/color][/bold]

While In-Character relationships such as being friends and enemies are perfectly acceptable, it must tie into something that has actually happened. To put it really simply;

You [bold][color=red]cannot[/bold][/color] hate someone in-character because you don’t like the player behind them.

You [bold][color=green]can[/bold][/color] hate someone in-character if the other character has done something to deserve it, like being a jerk to you in-character.

Preferential treatment (Both ways) must remain within logical in-character bounds.

[bold]Ex.[/bold] [color=green]In a mass casualty situation, saving your in-character friend/lover/partner, ect, over other individuals.[/color]

This is fine because it follows in-character logic, although it may come with consequences if you do this as a job that should prioritize other things, such as ignoring your charge as Blueshield Officer to save your buddy.

[bold]Ex.[/bold] [color=red]Giving John the Passenger All-Access, or a “Bridge Assistant" position because you both are long-time friends in-character.[/color]

This is not acceptable because this breaks in-character logic of the individual in the Command position. You’d get fired for doing something like that, which is where the in-character logic breaks.

[bold][color=#ff6200]Last shift’s disaster is not this shift’s problem[/color][/bold]

A Nuclear Operative shift where either everyone died, or lived, is not grounds for preparing for Nuclear Operatives in the next shift, or any other threat that happened previously in the shift before the current one. 

You must always operate under the assumption that the shift you are currently on will be a [bold][color=green]Green Shift[/color][/bold] until proven otherwise, unless your job explicitly requires you to look out for threats that may show up and threaten the lives of crew, such as [bold]Security[/bold] and the [bold]BlueShield/RedSword Officer[/bold].

This does not mean exempt jobs should operate under the assumption that it will be a [bold][color=blue]Blue Shift[/color][/bold] or [bold][color=red]Red Shift[/color][/bold], it simply means that they are allowed to be on the lookout for potential threats that may or may not appear.

## Corporate Secrets
[bold][color=#9819ff]Color[/color][/bold]

[bold][color=#9819ff]The Prometheus Protocol[/color][/bold]

The steps Command must take to begin detonation of the [bold]Onboard Nuclear Fission Device[/bold]

See: [bold][textlink="Prometheus Protocol" link="prometheus-protocol"][/bold]

The Captain, Head of Security & Magistrate are informed of the details of this protocol.

[bold][color=#9819ff]True Nature of Nuclear Operatives[/color][/bold]

Nuclear Operatives are not just terrorists, they are still employees of the respective corporation they “defected” from. NeoSol and NanoTrasen high-ups are both aware of the other side’s hostile forces, but do not openly call each other out on it because it could very easily spark a corporate war neither side wants. Instead, both sides are perfectly happy to continue to push the narrative that these are simply “rouge terrorists” with an agenda against both sides.

## Secure Information
[bold][color=#f00000]Color[/color][/bold]


[bold][color=#f00000]Prometheus Protocol Exists[/color][/bold]

Command and Security are aware that a protocol with this very name exists for the sole purpose of detonating the Onboard Nuclear Fission Device, but are not informed of the details of it, as the information is on a pure need-to-know basis.

[bold][color=#f00000]Origin Of Romerol Outbreaks[/color][/bold]

It is well known by Command and Security that Romerol is a biological weapon originally created by the Syndicate and utilized by infiltrators to try and trigger the detonation of the on-board nuclear device carried by corporate stations, due to the [bold]Concord Frontier Authority[/bold] having very strict containment protocols revolving around such a dangerous biological weapon being detected.

For handling an outbreak see: [bold][textlink="Romerol Outbreak Protocol" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

[bold][color=#f00000]Spider Clan’s Objective[/color][/bold]

All Ninjas sent by the Spider Clan have a singular goal, being to steal Corporate Research for their own purposes. How they achieve that goal,what damage they do, as well as how violent they can be vary by the individual ninja they send to the station. Whichever the case, you can rest assured that if there is a Ninja around, they will try to go after the Research Director’s Server, and steps should be taken to minimize the possibility of that happening.

For handling Ninjas, see: [bold][textlink="Ninja Protocol" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

[bold][color=#f00000]Revolutions Are Just USSP Takeovers[/color][/bold]

The fact that the USSP sends infiltrators to try and take over stations in the name of “Communism” is something Corporations are well aware of, as well as their methods. While not every “Revolting” Crew is a USSP-funded takeover, as there can be legitimate reasons for why a Crew does not want to work under current Command anymore, Security & Command should still be wary of any talk about such things, as it may be a sign that the USSP has planted agents on their station.

Arguably the most recognizable sign of a potential attempt to overthrow the station in the name of the USSP is the mass use of flashes against members of the Crew by the Crew, something that is normally innocuous in the hands of ordinary individuals, but that the USSP has managed to modify to their advantage to brainwash unfortunate individuals.

For confirming a USSP-Lead Revolt see: [bold][textlink="Signs of Revolutionary Activity" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

For handling a USSP-Lead Revolt see: [bold][textlink="Handling Revolutionary Activity" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

[bold][color=#f00000]Abductors Are Real[/color][/bold]

A common and debated topic among Spacers is the existence of the grey men simply known as “Abductors” - Command and Security are aware of the rumours being entirely true, and that they pose a real, albeit minor, threat to the station. 

Whilst they are scary at first, what with their teleportation technologies that do not rely on bluespace, or the highly advanced weapons they employ, they are for the most part harmless, as all they are interested in is performing “experiments” on crew, which typically involve swapping out normal organs of unfortunate individuals for their “experimental” ones. 

[bold]Security[/bold] can safely ignore the threat, so long as they do not interrupt station activity too much as extracting the alien organs and bringing them back to Central provide fairly valuable research on their own.

[bold]Command[/bold] should never be alone so long as there is an abductor threat, as while their abductions are not lethal, it will hamper productivity to have a head of a department suddenly disappear for some time. Keeping the Blueshield Officer with them, or just an employee of their department will do just fine.

For more details see: [bold][textlink="Abductor Protocol" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

[bold][color=#f00000]Paradox Clones are Real[/color][/bold]

Paradox clones are the result of cracks in reality varying from great incidents that ripple throughout other parallel realities and worlds, or just simple random chance based on quantum mechanics. Whatever the cause, these cracks, or “rifts” are inherently unstable and only last about as long as the average station-shift, leaving not much time to study the relatively rare phenomenon. When the “rift” closes, the paradox clone that originated from that rift will cease to exist.. if their counterpart from our universe is still alive. 

There is no officially proven method for the continued existence of a paradox clone besides replacing the original individual, however, creative [bold]Research Directors[/bold] have come up with methods in the past.

[bold]Security[/bold] must be cautious around them, and under no circumstances should the fact that their existence being temporary be revealed, as more often than not it will result in a desperate attempt to kill their other self in order to live. It is advised to monitor the two individuals, but not interfere unless one attempts to kill the other. 

[bold]Command[/bold] must come up with a plausible explanation as to why there is two Johns on shift, a tried but true method to explain this is to simply state an “accident” has occurred with the cloning process, resulting in more than one John being cloned and sent to the station at the same time, or that the system was accidentally triggered despite John not dying.

[bold]The Research Director[/bold], due to being an high-ranking expert in anomalous situations, is the [bold][color=#f00000]only one[/color][/bold] privy to [bold][color=#f00000]Classified Research[/color][/bold] on the topic of ensuring the survival of both the Paradox Clone, and the Original. These methods are;

- [bold][color=#f00000]Killing the Original right before the shift ends[/color][/bold]

This will “trick” our reality into believing only one individual currently exists when the rift closes. Revival of the Original afterwards will not erase the Paradox Clone as far as current research suggests, effectively exploiting a loophole in time and space. This should however be a last-resort, as.. It’s not exactly the best to kill an individual over this.

- [bold][color=#f00000]Cloning the Paradox Clone[/color][/bold]

Ship of Theseus. If you replace every component in a ship, is it still the same ship? According to Reality, it is not. By cloning the Paradox Clone you effectively grant them a temporal-stable body that will not be affected by the “rift” closing. 

- [bold][color=#f00000]Using a Desynchronizer right before the shift ends[/color][/bold]

Much like the first method, this tricks reality into believing there is only one individual currently alive due to shifting both of them temporarily into a different dimension. The Research Director must hand the desynchronizer to the clone and original, and instruct both of them to activate the device right before the shift-change, or evacuation shuttle, enters FTL.

[bold][color=#f00000]Nuclear Operatives Target Corporations[/color][/bold]

While the general threat of nuclear operatives is known to most Spacers operating in the Corporate Sector, it is under the assumption that they are just rogue terrorists lashing out to make a name for themselves, not that they have a specific agenda against the Corporations. 

They typically go after smaller targets in the area, but it is not out of the question that they may have the larger stations you work on in their crosshairs as some sort of bold statement. Historically, this does not work out well for them but it is a very real situation that can occur.

For handling a Nuclear Operative Attack see: [bold][textlink="Nuclear Operative Protocol" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

[bold][color=#f00000]Changeling Screening Is Imperfect[/color][/bold]

Corporate Screening to prevent Changelings from infiltrating stations does not have a 100% success rate in detection, either due to intentional sabotage by unknown third parties or a misplaced blood-test by a tired chemist. Whatever the case, on any given shift there may be a changeling, or even several, that have managed to pass through screening and are now actively trying to covertly survive off of unfortunate individuals.

For handling & detecting a Changeling see: [bold][textlink="Handling Changelings" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

For handling a Changeling Blood Test see: [bold][textlink="Blood Testing Procedures" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

[bold]Security[/bold] is advised to remain vigilant for any signs of Changeling activity aboard the station, and any reports of “odd” activity, such as weird fleshy noises or strange cyan-blue puddles being found in maintenance must be treated with the utmost importance and investigated over other issues, even above potential activity by Corporate Spies.

[bold]Command[/bold], upon reports of changeling activity, should not be alone with potentially dangerous crewmembers, nor by themselves at any time. Remaining in groups of 2-3 is the ideal number to prevent being isolated by a Changeling and eaten alive. They must also ensure the crew remains calm and does not panic when sightings of changeling activity is reported. Asking for Security Escorts, if Security can spare a few individuals for this task, is also acceptable.

[bold]Security & Command[/bold] are also aware of the abilities of Changelings due to previous shift incidents, classified reports, and CCTV footage providing ample information.. Essentially, if a Changeling can do it, the Corporation knows about it. As such, electronic or cybernetic based members of Security are heavily advised to not confront Changelings alone, as it will more than likely end up with them dead due to the inherent ability of Changelings to make chemical electro-magnetic pulses.

[bold][color=#f00000]Equipment Of Corporate Spies[/color][/bold]

There is a constant tug-of-war going on between Spies and Corporations over what technologies and tools they have access to, and how to operate them. Security & Command are briefed monthly on the known list of equipment as well as how they operate, but more often than not the exact method to operate said equipment has already changed by the time the briefing happens.

For handling Corporate Spies see: [bold][textlink="Handling Corporate Spies" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

This is to say, Security & Command are fully informed of what Corporate Spies can use, which means they are aware of all the different kinds of implanters, tools, weapons and other items in the uplink, but not how to operate the secret functions, such as using the hypopen as an injector. 

They are also aware PDAs & Headsets can be tampered with, but they need proof or enough circumstantial evidence to perform a search, due to the CFA’s privacy laws generally protecting individuals from random searches of telecommunication equipment, or personal digital assistant devices. Valid examples for searches are listed below;

### Headsets
- A telecommunications chip going missing from a headset that the suspect interacted with
- The suspect speaking into radio channels they should not have access to.
- The suspect speaking into an unknown channel that their headset should not have.

To elaborate, if the suspect has a medical headset, you know it can only have common and medical. So if you also have those channels, and see them speaking into the radio but not on either of those channels, you could assume they may have tampered with their headset.

- Multiple (2+) or Dangerous (Weapons, Explosives, Armor) Syndicate/Soviet Contraband found on their person.

### PDAs
- Seeing items mysteriously appearing into a suspect’s hand with no discernable cause.

Also grounds for an uplink or storage implant search, if an uplink isn't found on a PDA.

- An overbearing desire to hold onto their Shift-Mandated PDA while in the Brig.
- Multiple (2+) or Dangerous (Weapons, Explosives, Armor) Syndicate/Soviet Contraband found on their person.

### Implants
- An individual's DNA was found on an Implanter
- Mysteriously breaking out of handcuffs
- Talking into a radio that isn’t on their person
- Any other strange situation where the only explanation for what happened is implant use.

For handling an Implant Removal see: [bold][textlink="Implant Removal Procedures" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

If an individual is physically harmed by the search of an implant then this constitutes [bold]Minor Assault[/bold] and any further attempts must be stopped.

###In General:
If a random search is performed regardless of the targeted crew’s consent and without probable cause, this constitutes an [bold]Unlawful Search[/bold] and potentially [bold]Unlawful Detainment[/bold] if the individual is held in custody to perform the search. In this case the individual has a full legal right to sue Security and should get CFA staff involved as soon as possible.

This only applies if the alert level is [bold][color=green]Code Green[/bold][/color], as Security is fully permitted to perform random searches on [bold][color=blue]Code Blue[/bold][/color] or higher per [bold][textlink="Standard Operating Procedures" link="sop-intro"][/bold]

[bold][color=#f00000]Xenoborgs Are Real[/color][/bold]

Xenoborgs pose a real, credible threat to stations in deep space like the ones Corporate Crew are employed on, as well as any passing-by vessels. Caution is heavily advised around them as they typically field very strong laser weaponry, and possess smaller droids with advanced camouflage technology as to be effectively invisible to the naked eye that can abduct a person before they can even scream.

[bold]Security[/bold], when applicable, should wear armor that resists or outright reflects laser weaponry if Xenoborgs are in the sector as they do not have any kinetic armaments that the Corporations are aware of. They should also always be in groups of two or larger due to the ability of Xenoborgs to silently abduct lone individuals. 

For more detailed instructions see: [bold][textlink="Xenoborg Protocol" link="security-hos-almanac"][/bold]

[bold]Command[/bold] should never be on their own so long as a Xenoborg threat is present for the same reasons Security shouldn’t, and the Research Director should prioritize electro-magnetic pulse weaponry.

## Public Information
[color=#0af024]Color[/color]

[bold][color=#0af024]Zombies Are Real[/color][/bold]

The origin of the Zombie Virus, or as it’s more scientifically referred to as Romerol is generally known as the creation of a mad scientist’s attempt to create what they viewed to be a perfect person- someone without Ego or Identity. It backfired. They ended up creating a horrible monster with a disease that can spread and mutate rapidly, making it effectively impossible to create a permanent cure, leading the virus to be more or less accepted as a fact of life in society.

No one really knows how an outbreak starts in a particular sector, station or planet, but whispers and rumors always attribute it to a bad actor, due to the rapid incubation time not allowing for infected individuals to walk around long without succumbing to the virus. Official stances by various planetary governments always maintain that an outbreak happened from an animal, asymptomatic individual, or accidental chemical leak however.

Basic information, like needing to aim for the head to properly kill a zombie, or to wear Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) and bite-proof articles of clothing in an active outbreak is known.

[bold][color=#0af024]Revolutions Happen[/color][/bold]

While the CFA diligently works to keep working conditions aboard Corporate Space stations at an acceptable level, their work does mostly pertain to preventing any violation of Space Law aboard their stations, and it is generally up to a Corporate’s Standard Operating Procedure and their enforcers to keep things within an acceptable range.

This does mean things unfortunately slip through the cracks, legal technicalities that don’t actually violate any laws but are just not great to work under, or other shady business practices. Naturally, working under these conditions can have an individual, or groups of individuals, get fed up and refuse to work. While trying to take over an entire station is certainly an extreme method of doing this, it can partially be understandable due to going through the Union if no laws have been violated, generally being a rather unpleasant and lengthy process as it involves arguing with Corporate Lawyers.

Whispers about certain Revolutions actually being just mass-brainwashing attempts by the USSP have circulated around, but most believe the USSP to be a somewhat benevolent force that stands for Worker’s Rights, as most attempted takeovers have their backing. Of course, some simply believe the USSP is jumping on the chance to try and extend their reach by having the station become their property.

[bold][color=#0af024]Changelings Are Real[/color][/bold]

Changelings are shapeshifting monsters, attributed to a particular species of parasite found on a long forgotten rimworld planet. The initial infection is attributed to a scientist getting too close to the native-plantlife of that planet and having a changeling slug attach itself to their brainstem.

Ever since that incident, Sentient Changelings have propagated using the (most of the time) still-living bodies of unfortunate victims, taking over their body and mutating their mind into something entirely unrecognizable. They are considered an existential threat to civilization at large, due to their ability to seamlessly blend into society and potentially take over important political figures to try and push their own agenda.

Crew members of Corporate Stations (as well as individuals employed in government facilities) go through regular blood-tests before and after every shift to confirm everyone onboard is not a changeling in disguise, and is therefore safe on station from the changeling threat. While changelings may rarely sneak onboard the station somehow, it is not a general concern of the crew.

Spacers are not too aware of the abilities of changelings outside from the obvious shapeshifting, though the “Changeling Sting” specifically has been propagated throughout various forms of social media, television shows and even movies. 

Basic information of how to spot a changeling is known by society at large, and come down to three oversimplified tests;

###Red Blood, Bad Blood
While certain species naturally have red blood, something like a Vox which normally bleeds ammonia-based blood instead bleeding red blood is a very clear sign of that individual potentially being a changeling, but does not outright confirm it. 

This is due to the fact certain individuals utilize Genetic Engineering to change the color of their blood to be “stylish”

###Ravenous Hunger
Excluding Vulpkanin & Cybernetically Modified individuals which are known for their voracious appetite, an individual constantly wanting to eat food to the point of shaking from hunger or even attempting to cannibalize other individuals to satisfy their hunger can be a sign that they are a Changeling. 

Although it may also be a sign that the individual is infected with Romerol, so this is not a perfect science.

###Fleshmorphing
This is the only guaranteed sign of a Changeling, as nothing science has created comes even close to the control the changeling parasite has over an individual’s biomass. Sudden fleshy weapons, keratin coated body armor, or shifting into an entirely different animal or individual must be reported to local authorities immediately, and local authorities are given the legal power to execute the Changeling on the spot if they bear witness to it. 

Blood-Testing is still required to legally confirm they are a changeling for incineration, however.

[bold][color=#0af024]Nuclear Operatives Are Real[/color][/bold]

Nuclear Operatives, or as they are more commonly referred to as “Nukies” are a real threat that you can encounter in space. The two main factions, Lambda Hardliners and Gorlex Marauders are officially listed within the CFA’s terrorist organisation registry. They earned the name by getting their hands on WMDs (Weapons of Mass Destruction) and successfully managing to set them off when they originally split from their respective corporate entity, not at the same time of course.

Lambda Hardliners, originated from NanoTrasen
Gorlex Marauders originated from NeoSol

Nukies prefer to attack smaller targets, such as outposts, lone vessels and rarely small stations. It is assumed that they are simply unable to take on bigger targets, as proven by repeated attacks against NeoSol and NanoTrasen stations that have always failed, either being thwarted by Emergency Response teams, or the local Security force employed by their respective corporation. This, combined with the Changeling threat, relative isolation of Corporate Stations from Emergency Response Teams, and other station-ending threats that can be encountered, has led to the more recent militarization of Station Security for both corporations, with special CFA permits being granted for heavier weapons that are typically restricted to military use only.

As such, crews of Corporate Stations are not particularly concerned by the threat of a Nuclear Operative Attack, because even in the extremely unlikely chance they do appear, they will not succeed based on historical precedence. 

Due to the origins of the Nuclear Squads, a persistent rumor that is always downplayed by the Corporations is the fact that they very well may actually still be working for the corporation they split from. There’s never been any solid proof presented, but the more conspiratorial individuals are quick to point out how odd it is Lambda Hardliners never attempt to attack NanoTrasen assets, or how the same could be said for the Gorlex Marauders. The Official stance on this matter is that they simply still hold a strange sense of loyalty from the faction they were disavowed from.

[bold][color=#0af024]Ninjas Are Real[/color][/bold]

While most “Ninja”s are simply high-tech weeaboo cosplayers that don’t really have any ill-intent or sense of honor, actual Ninja Clans still have managed to persist to modern-day with fairly advanced technologies that make them a formidable foe. The most well-known is the Spider Clan, with their signature black and green color-scheme. They are listed as a Terrorist Organization with the CFA due to their repeated attacks against Corporate Stations, and even some Governmental entities all in the name of some sort of “honor” and generational-spanning feuds that precedes the age of Faster-Than-Light travel.

Not all real Ninjas are terrorists however, some simply want to pass on their honor-bound traditions and way of life to their next of kin or are vigilantes taking law into their own hands, which while make them criminal by definition, they are generally seen with a positive light by most individuals even if the law-enforcement entities do not.

[bold][color=#0af024]Space Wizards Are Real[/color][/bold]

The average Spacer is aware that Atherians, or “Wizards” are travelers from another dimension simply known as the Aether, or sometimes referred to as the “Overworld” and that they can perform seemingly magical or impossible things. General caution is advised around these individuals, as they are generally unpredictable and potentially dangerous due to their inherent ability to simply conjure things into existence, including more harmful things like fireballs.

[bold][color=#0af024]Xenoborgs Are Rumored To Be Real[/color][/bold]

The average spacer is well-aware of stories and rumors about Xenoborgs, where unfortunate individuals are abducted into their hivemind, never to see the light of day again. Most don’t really take stock in these stories however, and are quick to write it off as people simply being paranoid about “blue borgs in space”

[bold][color=#0af024]Abductors Are Rumored To Be Real[/color][/bold]

Tales of “little grey men” abducting people in circular ships have always been a staple in most cultures, even in pre-FTL civilizations. While it is certainly odd that so many cultures have their own variant of “aliens from space” that all happen to either be green or grey with black beady eyes, it’s handwaved off as a fascination with space and the lack of creativity most would have in trying to come up with something truly alien. 

However.. Sightings of these “grey men” have been popping up more frequently as technology advances, with wild stories of unfortunate individuals having their organs stolen and replaced with entirely alien ones. However, most consider these exaggerated stories, and the strange organs or grey individuals as products of Genetic Engineering rather than something truly “alien”

[bold][color=#0af024]Corporate Sabotage Happens[/color][/bold]

Traitors to the Corporation or Corporate Spies, while not incredibly common, are more often than not a frequent sight on Corporate Stations. Why they are here and what they want to do are not well-known to the average Spacer, but it doesn’t take a genius to know whatever they’re here for, it’s not exactly a good thing. Crew of Corporate Stations are advised to report any suspicious activity to Security as you never know when something strange but easy to write off is actually the actions of a corporate saboteur!

[bold][color=#0af024]High Value Targets Are.. High Value[/color][/bold]

The average Corporate Crew member knows that high value targets are exactly that, expensive pieces of technology that the Company produces at great cost. It doesn’t exactly take a genius to figure out that the shady passenger walking into Medical asking about the location of the [bold]Chief Medical Officer’s Hypospray[/bold] may have less than savory intentions revolving around the item, as an example.

</Document>